A Guide to the Joseph B. Benedetti Papers 1983-1997
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Joseph B. Benedetti Papers 1983-1997
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 271
37 linear feet
Joseph B. Benedetti
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated to Special Collections and Archives by Mr. Benedetti in May 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
Joseph Benedict Benedetti served as a legislator representing parts of the Richmond, Virginia metropolitan area first as a state delegate (1983-1986, 68th District)and later as state senator (1986-1997, 10th Senatorial District) in Virginia's General Assembly. Benedetti, a Republican, was appointed by Gov. James Gilmore to serve as head of the Virginia Department of Criminal Justice Services in 1997. He left that position in December 2001.
Born in Richmond in 1929, Benedetti received an A.B. from the College of William and Mary and a J.D. from the University of Richmond Law School. He reached the rank of major in the U.S. Army Reserve and served in Japan, 1946-1947; Korea, 1951-1952; and during the Berlin Crisis, 1960-1961. He worked as a lawyer in the firm of Benedetti, Gilmore, Warthen and Dalton. He ran unsuccessfully for Virginia's Attorney General's office in 1989.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists largely of printed information and correspondence from special interests and Benedetti's constituents concerning issues on a wide range of subjects dealt by Virginia legislators in the late 1980s and early 1990s. Also included are copies of bills in their various versions, newspaper clippings, newsletters, reports, information on Richmond and Virginia agencies and civic organizations, and copies of Benedetti's responses to constituents' letters.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged as received, in alphabetical order by subject. Additions to the collection were interfiled alphabetically and then chronologicaly in Series one (n.d., 1981-1993). Series Two (1986-1997) consists of materials to the collection in 1996 and 1998.
Contents List
- Series One, n.d. 1981-1993
  - Abortion 1982-1985 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Abortion 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Abortion 1984-1985 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Abortion, Teenage 1990 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Agess for Attorney General 1993 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Agenda for VA--Wilder 1990 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Aging 1984-1986 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Aging 1990 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Aid to Dependent Children 1986 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - AIDS 1988 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - AIDS Education Project 1988 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Airport 1989 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Allen, George for Governor 1993 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - American Legislative Exchange Counsel (ALEC) 1993 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Animal Experimentation 1990 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Annexation 1990 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Appropriations, n.d. 1982 (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Arts 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Arts Awards--Richmond 1989 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Attorney General: The Civil Digest opinions 1983-1984 (Box-folder 2.12)
  - Attorney Genral: correspondence 1983-1985 (Box-folder 2.13)
  - Attorney General: Dennis Peterson 1992 (Box-folder 2.14)
  - Attorney General's Office 1983-1986 (Box-folder 2.15)
  - Audiovisual Materials: Use by Virginia Students 1984 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Auto Insurance Costs 1990 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Babalas, Senator Peter K.: conflict of interest 1986-1987 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Banks and Insurance 1991 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Bell, Patrick (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Belle Isle 1985-1986 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Benedetti: Bills 1986 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Benedetti: Budget Speech 1991 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Benedetti: Special Session 1986 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Binding Arbirtation (Box-folder 3.10)
  - Bingo Laws 1984-1986 (Box-folder 3.11)
  - Bill Tracking 1992-1995 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Bills and Summaries 1990 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Blab T.V. 1990-1991 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Blue Cross Blue Shield 1988 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Bond Issues 1992 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Bonds, Pledge 1990 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - Bottle bill 1985 (Box-folder 4.7)
  - Budget 1984-1986 (Box-folder 4.8)
  - Budget 1990 (Box-folder 4.9)
  - Budget Analysis: F. Tait 1991 (Box-folder 4.10)
  - Budget Control 1991 (Box-folder 4.11)
  - Budget Oversight Committee 1994 (Box-folder 4.12)
  - Budget Report: 1984-1986 (Box-folder 4.13)
  - Budget Report: revised 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4.14)
  - Business 1983-1985 (Box-folder 4.15)
  - Byrd Airport 1984 (Box-folder 4.16)
  - CADRE 1990 (Box-folder 4.17)
  - Campaign 1995 (Box-folder 4.18)
  - Campaign Ideas 1990 (Box-folder 4.19)
  - Capital Area Assembly 1991 (Box-folder 4.20)
  - Captial Representation Resource Center--Board of Directors 1994 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Census 2000 (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Census Fact Sheets 1992 (Box-folder 5.3)
  - Central VA Legislative Delegation 1988 (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Certificate of Public Need 1988 (Box-folder 5.5)
  - Chesapeake Bay 1982-1984 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Chesapeake Bay 1983-1985 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - Chesapeake Bay 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - Chesapeake Bay Act 1991 (Box-folder 5.9)
  - Chesapeake Bay Act--Impact Meeting 1990 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Chesapeake Bay Commission 1989 (Box-folder 5.11)
  - Chief Patron Report through 91 session 1991 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Child Abuse Statue of Limitations 1990 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Child Care 1985-1986 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Child care, day care centers 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Child Care and Early Childhood Programs 1990 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Child Support 1984-1985 (Box-folder 6.6)
  - Child Support Automated System 1989 (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Child Support Enforcement Legislative Program 1990 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Child Support Joint Sub-committee HJR 341 1988 (Box-folder 6.9)
  - Child Support, Rehabilitation Subcommittee 1981-1987 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - Children, child abuse 1982-1985 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - City of Richmond: Legislative Program 1991 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Clean Air 1990 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Clean Fuels Subcommittee 1994 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Coal industry 1984 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Coal slurry pipeline 1983-1985 (Box-folder 7.6)
  - Coal slurry pipeline 1983-1985 (Box-folder 7.7)
  - Coal slurry pipeline 1983-1984 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Cocaine initative, n.d. (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Collection Agencies SB 995 1993-1994 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Combined Sewer Overflow 1989 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Commercial Drivers License Act 1989 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Common Cause of Virginia 1982-1983 (Box-folder 8.6)
  - Community Action Agency 1987 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - Compensation--State Employees 1990 (Box-folder 8.8)
  - Conferderate Home 1988 (Box-folder 8.9)
  - Confiscation--Firearms 1988 (Box-folder 8.10)
  - Conflict of interest 1982-1986 (Box-folder 8.11)
  - Conflict of interest 1984-1986 (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Conflict of Interest: statement 1992 (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Conflict of Interest: Partners and Associates (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Congressional Liaison Status Report 1988 (Box-folder 9.4)
  - Conservation/Natural resources 1984-1985 (Box-folder 9.5)
  - Constitutional changes proposal 1986 (Box-folder 9.6)
  - Constitutional Convention 1988 (Box-folder 9.7)
  - Contractors 1982-1983 (Box-folder 9.8)
  - Corrections 1982-1983 (Box-folder 9.9)
  - Corrections: parole (S.B. 105) 1983-1984 (Box-folder 9.10)
  - Correspondence 1985-1986 (Box-folder 9.11)
  - Correspondence 1988 (Box-folder 10.1)
  - Correspondence 1990 (Box-folder 10.2)
  - Correspondence 1993 (Box-folder 10.3)
  - Correspondence after March 1, 1988 (Box-folder 10.5)
  - Correspondence: Constituent 1989 (Box-folder 10.6)
  - Correspondence: General 1988 (Box-folder 10.7)
  - Correspondence: General 1989 (Box-folder 11.1)
  - Correspondence: General 1990 (Box-folder 11.2)
  - Correspondence: Legislative, January-April 1986 (Box-folder 11.3)
  - Correspondence: Legislative, April-December 1986 (Box-folder 11.4)
  - Correspondence: Legislative, April-December 1986 (Box-folder 11.5)
  - Correspondence: legislative 1988 (Box-folder 11.6)
  - Correspondence: Legislative 1989 (Box-folder 12.1)
  - Correspondence: Legislative 1990 (Box-folder 12.2)
  - Legislative 1990 (Box-folder 12.3)
  - Correspondence: Legislative 1991 (Box-folder 12.4)
  - Correspondence: Legislative January 1, 1989 (Box-folder 13.1)
  - Correspondence: Oregon Hill 1989-1990 (Box-folder 13.2)
  - Correspondence: Prior to 1989 session 1988 (Box-folder 13.3)
  - Correspondence: Senate 1989 (Box-folder 13.4)
  - Courts: Appeal/Juries 1983 (Box-folder 13.5)
  - Courts: General District/Intermediate Appellate 1983-1984 (Box-folder 13.6)
  - Courts: Intermediate Appellate 1983-1984 (Box-folder 14.1)
  - Courts of Justice: Judicial Interview 1993 (Box-folder 14.2)
  - Crime 1982-1985 (Box-folder 14.3)
  - Crime in VA: State Police report 1990 (Box-folder 14.4)
  - Crime and Violence by Students on school property 1992 (Box-folder 14.5)
  - Cultural Laureate Foundation, Inc. 1974-1985 (Box-folder 14.6)
  - Day Care 1990 (Box-folder 14.7)
  - Death Penalty: Drug Killings 1988-1989 (Box-folder 14.8)
  - Debt Counseling (H.B. 389) 1986 (Box-folder 14.9)
  - Dillon Rule 1992 (Box-folder 14.10)
  - Directory of GOP Legislative Candidates 1991 (Box-folder 14.11)
  - Divorce Law 1983-1985 (Box-folder 14.12)
  - Divorcement and Open Supply 1990 (Box-folder 14.13)
  - Down Zoning-Fairfax County (Box-folder 14.14)
  - Drinking Age 1982-1984 (Box-folder 15.1)
  - Drug Abuse 1983-1985 (Box-folder 15.2)
  - Drug Free workplace 1990 (Box-folder 15.3)
  - Drug Free workplace 1991 (Box-folder 15.4)
  - Drug Laws--Michigan 1988 (Box-folder 15.5)
  - Drug Programs--testing, n.d. (Box-folder 15.6)
  - Drugs 1984-1986 (Box-folder 16.1)
  - Drunk driving 1983-1984 (Box-folder 16.2)
  - Drunk Driving Legislation: Constitutional Aspects 1987 (Box-folder 16.3)
  - Durable Medical Equipment 1990 (Box-folder 16.4)
  - Early Retirement (VEGA) 1991 (Box-folder 16.5)
  - Education: Higher 1983-1985 (Box-folder 16.6)
  - Education: Higher 1983-1985 (Box-folder 16.7)
  - Education: Home 1984 (Box-folder 17.1)
  - Education: legislative positions, various agencies 1985-1986 (Box-folder 17.2)
  - Education: miscellaneous 1984-1986 (Box-folder 17.3)
  - Education reform--clippings 1990 (Box-folder 17.4)
  - Education reform: Kentucky 1990 (Box-folder 17.5)
  - Education: Standards of Quality 1986 (Box-folder 17.6)
  - Education: Virginia Tech (Va.-Md. Regional College of Veterinary Medicine) 1984 (Box-folder 17.7)
  - Education: Vocational 1984-1986 (Box-folder 17.8)
  - Educational reform 1989 (Box-folder 17.9)
  - Efficiency in Government, Governor's Commission 1986 (Box-folder 17.10)
  - Efficiency in Government 1988 (Box-folder 17.11)
  - Election: Sabato 1989 (Box-folder 17.12)
  - Elections, State Board of 1985 (Box-folder 17.13)
  - Eligibility for Medicaid (Box-folder 17.14)
  - Emergency Medical Services 1981-1985 (Box-folder 18.1)
  - Energy 1983-1984 (Box-folder 18.2)
  - Engineers, Consulting 1983-1984 (Box-folder 18.3)
  - Ethics 1992 (Box-folder 18.4)
  - Executive Branch reorganization 1984 (Box-folder 18.5)
  - Eye Care Project, National 1986 (Box-folder 18.6)
  - Family Courts Pilot Project (Box-folder 18.7)
  - Family Life Education 1987-1988 (Box-folder 18.8)
  - Family Life Education 1989 (Box-folder 18.9)
  - Family Life Education 1989 (Box-folder 18.10)
  - Family Life Education: Opt Out Complaints 1990 (Box-folder 18.11)
  - Family Life Policy 1988 (Box-folder 18.12)
  - Farris for Lt. Governor 1993 (Box-folder 19.1)
  - Federal Funding State Domestic programs 1987 (Box-folder 19.2)
  - Federal retirees 1982-1983 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - Fetal Tissue Transplantation 1990 (Box-folder 19.4)
  - Fish Passage 1992 (Box-folder 19.5)
  - Fishing licenses 1984 (Box-folder 19.6)
  - Fluoridation 1974-1983 (Box-folder 19.7)
  - Freedom of Information 1983-1984 (Box-folder 19.8)
  - Freedom of Information HJR 100 1989 (Box-folder 19.9)
  - Gambling 1984 (Box-folder 19.10)
  - Gas, Commonwealth 1985 (Box-folder 19.11)
  - Gas, Natural 1983 (Box-folder 19.12)
  - Gay Alliance 1985 (Box-folder 19.13)
  - General Laws 1984-1987 (Box-folder 19.14)
  - General Obligation Bond 1992 (Box-folder 19.15)
  - Giarratano, Joseph M. 1991 (Box-folder 19.16)
  - Gilmore for Attorney General 1993 (Box-folder 19.17)
  - Governor Charles S. Robb 1982-1986 (Box-folder 19.18)
  - Governor's Commission on Ethics 1992-1993 (Box-folder 19.19)
  - Governor's Office Staff 1990 (Box-folder 19.20)
  - Guardianship in Va 1989 (Box-folder 19.21)
  - Gubernatorial term of office 1985 (Box-folder 19.22)
  - Gun control 1982-1983 (Box-folder 20.1)
  - Gun Control 1991 (Box-folder 20.2)
  - Gun Control Study Committee: Richmond City Council 1991 (Box-folder 20.3)
  - Handicapped 1982-1985 (Box-folder 20.4)
  - Handicapped, Visually 1982-1983 (Box-folder 20.5)
  - Harper v. Department of Taxation 1993 (Box-folder 20.6)
  - Health Care: Insurance 1993 (Box-folder 20.7)
  - Health Care: miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box-folder 20.8)
  - Health Care: Pepper Commission 1991 (Box-folder 20.9)
  - Health issues 1984-1985 (Box-folder 20.10)
  - Health issues 1985-1986 (Box-folder 20.11)
  - Health, Mental 1983-1985 (Box-folder 21.1)
  - Health, Mental and Mental Retardation, Department of 1984-1985 (Box-folder 21.2)
  - Health Regulatory Board 1985 (Box-folder 21.3)
  - Health, State Department of 1982-1985 (Box-folder 21.4)
  - Health Statistics: Richmond 1989 (Box-folder 21.5)
  - Health, Welfare, and Institutions: involuntary commitment 1984-1985 (Box-folder 22.1)
  - Health, Welfare, and Institutions: occupational and respiratory therapists 1983 (Box-folder 22.2)
  - Henrico County 1985-1987 (Box-folder 22.3)
  - Henrico County Legislative Program 1990 (Box-folder 22.4)
  - Henrico County Supervisor 1990 (Box-folder 22.5)
  - Henrico Legislative Program 1990 (Box-folder 22.6)
  - Highway Funding (Box-folder 22.7)
  - Highway Program 1986-1987 (Box-folder 22.8)
  - Historic Preservation: Grants and Report by Gov. Comm. 1989 (Box-folder 22.9)
  - Historic Richmond Foundation, Inc. 1990 (Box-folder 22.10)
  - Historical landmarks 1983-1985 (Box-folder 22.11)
  - Home based services funding 1990 (Box-folder 22.12)
  - Home Builders Association of Virginia 1982-1985 (Box-folder 22.13)
  - Homeless 1986-1989 (Box-folder 22.14)
  - Hospital Association, Virginia 1982-1985 (Box-folder 23.1)
  - Hospital costs 1983-1984 (Box-folder 23.2)
  - House of Delegates rules 1982-1984 (Box-folder 23.3)
  - Housing: Adult and Group Homes 1985-1986 (Box-folder 23.4)
  - Housing: Mentally ill 1985 (Box-folder 23.5)
  - Housing: Redevelopment 1983-1985 (Box-folder 23.6)
  - Housing: Partnership Fund (Va) 1989 (Box-folder 23.7)
  - How a Bill becomes a Law/Legislative District Maps (Box-folder 23.8)
  - Human Relations 1984 (Box-folder 23.9)
  - Human Rights 1985 (Box-folder 23.10)
  - Humanities and Public Policy, Virginia Foundation for 1981-1984 (Box-folder 24.1)
  - Hunger and Poverty in Va 1988 (Box-folder 24.2)
  - Hunter safety 1986 (Box-folder 24.3)
  - Illiteracy 1989 (Box-folder 24.4)
  - Impact Fees 1989 (Box-folder 24.5)
  - Income Tax Credits 1989 (Box-folder 24.6)
  - Indian head Division Association 1991 (Box-folder 24.7)
  - Indians, Commission on 1983 (Box-folder 24.8)
  - Indigent Health Care Fund 1992 (Box-folder 24.9)
  - Indigent Health Care Trust 1989 (Box-folder 24.10)
  - Industry, business 1983-1984 (Box-folder 24.11)
  - Infant morality 1985 (Box-folder 24.12)
  - Initiative and Referendum 1984 (Box-folder 24.13)
  - Instream Flow Policy Advisory group 1988 (Box-folder 24.14)
  - Instream Flow Workshop 1988 (Box-folder 24.15)
  - Insurance 1983-1985 (Box-folder 24.16)
  - Insurance industry 1989 (Box-folder 24.17)
  - Intergovernmental Cooperation, Commission on 1992 (Box-folder 24.18)
  - Invitations 1986 (Box-folder 24.19)
  - Italian-American Society of Richmond (Box-folder 24.20)
  - Joint Legislative and Audit Commission 1985-1986 (Box-folder 25.1)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) 1992 (Box-folder 25.2)
  - Joint Republican Caucus 1990 (Box-folder 25.3)
  - Joint Republican Caucus 1990 1990 (Box-folder 25.4)
  - Joint Republican Caucus: Wintergreen Retreat 12/5/92 (Box-folder 25.5)
  - Judicial appointments, nominations 1985 (Box-folder 25.6)
  - Judicial selection 1989 (Box-folder 25.7)
  - Jurisdiction of VA Court of Appeals 1988-1990 (Box-folder 25.8)
  - Justice Fellowship 1990 (Box-folder 25.9)
  - Juvenile Court Judge 1985-1986 (Box-folder 25.10)
  - Juveniles in jail 1983-1984 (Box-folder 25.11)
  - Juveniles in Jail, Joint Subcommittee to Study the Detention of 1983 (Box-folder 26.1)
  - Knights of Columbus 1992 (Box-folder 26.2)
  - Labor Policy 1988 (Box-folder 26.3)
  - Land Use: Speech (Box-folder 26.4)
  - Landfill use fee and hydrant tax (Richmond) HB 1393 1993 (Box-folder 26.5)
  - Landlord Tenant Act 1984-1985 (Box-folder 26.6)
  - Lawson, Katherine--Family Issues 1990 (Box-folder 26.7)
  - League of Women Voters 1982-1983 (Box-folder 26.8)
  - Leftover Legislative work (Box-folder 26.9)
  - Legalizing Drugs 1989 (Box-folder 26.10)
  - Legislation 1985 (Box-folder 26.11)
  - Legislation, possible 1989 (Box-folder 26.12)
  - Legislation, possible 1990 (Box-folder 27.1)
  - Legislation, possible 1991 (Box-folder 27.2)
  - Legislation, possible 1993 (Box-folder 27.3)
  - Legislation, proposed 1983 (Box-folder 27.4)
  - Legislation, proposed 1985 (Box-folder 27.5)
  - Legislative aides, pages, interns 1982-1986 (Box-folder 27.6)
  - Legislative intent 1989 (Box-folder 27.7)
  - Libraries 1984 (Box-folder 27.8)
  - Literary Fund 1986 (Box-folder 27.9)
  - Literary Fund 1992 (Box-folder 27.10)
  - Little Sisters of the Poor Board 1993 (Box-folder 27.11)
  - Local Government 1986-1987 (Box-folder 27.12)
  - Local Government Issues 1990 (Box-folder 27.13)
  - Long Term Care 1985 (Box-folder 28.1)
  - Lottery 1983-1985 (Box-folder 28.2)
  - Lottery 1986 (Box-folder 28.3)
  - Lottery 1989 (Box-folder 28.4)
  - Lottery, n.d. (Box-folder 28.5)
  - Lottery Funds Project 1990 (Box-folder 28.6)
  - Lottery Proceeds 1990 (Box-folder 28.7)
  - Mailing information, n.d. 1983 (Box-folder 28.8)
  - Maps--political districts (Box-folder 28.9)
  - Marine Sanitation Devices, Joint Subcommittee 1984 (Box-folder 28.10)
  - Mary Washington College, name change request, n.d. 1985-1986 (Box-folder 28.11)
  - Massino's Casinos 1990 (Box-folder 28.12)
  - Mathematics and Science Center Foundation (Box-folder 28.13)
  - Media 1984-1985 (Box-folder 29.1)
  - Medicaid 1983-1984 (Box-folder 29.2)
  - Medicaid Eligibility 1987 (Box-folder 29.3)
  - Medical malpractice 1984-1985 (Box-folder 29.4)
  - Medical Society of Virginia 1982-1984 (Box-folder 29.5)
  - Medical Waste Incineration Facility--Unimed 1991 (Box-folder 29.6)
  - Medicare Supplement Options VSRS 1990 (Box-folder 29.7)
  - Memorial resolutions 1983-1987 (Box-folder 29.8)
  - Mentally Disabled 1989 (Box-folder 29.9)
  - Miller (Clint) Amendments 1990 (Box-folder 29.10)
  - Miller for Governor 1993 (Box-folder 29.11)
  - Minter, George 1992 (Box-folder 29.12)
  - Miscellaneous legislative issues 1983, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 29.13)
  - Mopeds 1978, 1985 (Box-folder 29.14)
  - Moore, Mel 1991 (Box-folder 29.15)
  - Murder, Capital (H.B. 269) 1986 (Box-folder 29.16)
  - NAACP 1983 (Box-folder 29.17)
  - Nance, Thomas N.--City of Richmond 1991 (Box-folder 29.18)
  - National Conference of State Legislature 1996 (Box-folder 29.19)
  - Natural Death Act 1982-1985 (Box-folder 29.20)
  - Neighborhood Watch; crime prevention 1981-1984 (Box-folder 30.1)
  - News clippings 1985-1986 (Box-folder 30.2)
  - News clippings 1989 (Box-folder 30.3)
  - News clippings 1990 (Box-folder 30.4)
  - Newsletter 1986 (Box-folder 30.5)
  - Newsletter 1987 (Box-folder 30.6)
  - Newsletter 1988 (Box-folder 30.7)
  - Newsletter 1989 (Box-folder 30.8)
  - Newsletter 1990 (Box-folder 30.9)
  - Newsletter 1991 (Box-folder 30.10)
  - Newsletters: from Benedetti 1983-1985 (Box-folder 30.11)
  - Newsletters: miscellaneous 1983-1986 (Box-folder 31.1)
  - North, Oliver 1994 (Box-folder 31.2)
  - North-South Summit Conference 1984 (Box-folder 31.3)
  - Notice Probate Legislation 1991 (Box-folder 31.4)
  - Nuclear Waste sites 1986 (Box-folder 31.5)
  - Nuclear weapons 1983 (Box-folder 31.6)
  - Nursing homes 1983-1984 (Box-folder 31.7)
  - Off Track Betting 1990 (Box-folder 31.8)
  - Opinion Poll: VFRW 1989 (Box-folder 31.9)
  - Outcome Based Education 1993 (Box-folder 31.10)
  - PAC's (Box-folder 31.11)
  - Page Applications 1991 (Box-folder 31.12)
  - Page Application 1992 (Box-folder 31.13)
  - Page Applications 1994 (Box-folder 31.14)
  - Page Applications 1995 (Box-folder 31.15)
  - Parental Leave 1991 (Box-folder 31.16)
  - Parental Notification 1990 (Box-folder 31.17)
  - Partnership for Urban Va 1994 (Box-folder 31.18)
  - Patrick Henry Memorial Commission 1986 (Box-folder 32.1)
  - Pension Tax--Special Session 1989 (Box-folder 32.2)
  - Pesticide Regulations 1989 (Box-folder 32.3)
  - Petroleum Products Franchise Act 1991 (Box-folder 32.4)
  - Philpott leadership Committee 1993 (Box-folder 32.5)
  - Pierce, Stewart: constituent 1982-1987 (Box-folder 32.6)
  - Pierce, Stewart 1990 (Box-folder 32.7)
  - Podiatry 1983-1984 (Box-folder 32.8)
  - Police Athletic League 1993 (Box-folder 32.9)
  - Population 1983-1984 (Box-folder 32.10)
  - Port of Richmond 1990 (Box-folder 32.11)
  - Postal Information 1991 (Box-folder 32.12)
  - Postage use 1986 (Box-folder 33.1)
  - Preneed Funeral Contracts Subcommittee 1994 (Box-folder 33.2)
  - Prescription Drug 1989 (Box-folder 33.3)
  - Prescription Insurance State Retirees 1989 (Box-folder 33.4)
  - Preservation Act: Ecology Issues 1988-1989 (Box-folder 33.5)
  - Press Conference (Box-folder 33.6)
  - Prison and Jail Overcrowding 1989 (Box-folder 33.7)
  - Prison Overcrowding 1990 (Box-folder 33.8)
  - Privileges and Elections 1993 (Box-folder 33.9)
  - Prior, Gordon 1993 (Box-folder 33.10)
  - PRO-STAR 1991 (Box-folder 33.11)
  - Probation Office, District 1 1991 (Box-folder 33.12)
  - Proprietary Child Care Association of VA 1992 (Box-folder 33.13)
  - Prompt pay 1984-1985 (Box-folder 33.14)
  - Questionaires 1989 (Box-folder 33.15)
  - Questionaires 1995 (Box-folder 33.16)
  - Questionaires, candidate 1982-1984 (Box-folder 34.1)
  - Questionaires, constituent 1991 (Box-folder 34.2)
  - Questionaire, constituent: responses 1985 (Box-folder 34.3)
  - Questionaire, constituent: results 1984-1985 (Box-folder 34.4)
  - Radioactive Waste Repository Site 1986 (Box-folder 34.5)
  - Recyclable Materials 1990 (Box-folder 34.6)
  - Recycling 1990 (Box-folder 34.7)
  - Recycling 1991 (Box-folder 34.8)
  - Redistricting 1991 (Box-folder 34.9)
  - Rehabilitation and Social Services Legislation: U.S. (Bliley) (Box-folder 34.10)
  - Real Estate 1983-1984 (Box-folder 34.11)
  - Real Estate Appraisals Model Law 1989 (Box-folder 35.1)
  - Repeal of State Sales tax on food and Drugs, cost of 1989 (Box-folder 35.2)
  - Republican Advance 1988 (Box-folder 35.3)
  - Republican Advance 1989 (Box-folder 35.4)
  - Republican Advance 1990 (Box-folder 35.5)
  - Republican Bills 1989 (Box-folder 35.6)
  - Republican Caucus 1982-1985 (Box-folder 35.7)
  - Republican Caucus 1983-1984 (Box-folder 35.8)
  - Republican Caucus 1986 (Box-folder 35.9)
  - Republican Caucus 1989-1993 (Box-folder 35.10)
  - Republican Caucus 1990 (Box-folder 35.11)
  - Republican Caucus: Campaign plan 1989 (Box-folder 35.12)
  - Republican Caucus: Finance Committee 1990 (Box-folder 35.13)
  - Republican Caucus: Fundraising 1988-1991 (Box-folder 36.1)
  - Republican Caucus: Organization and Future Planning 1987-1988 (Box-folder 36.2)
  - Republican Caucus: Policy Committee 1993 (Box-folder 36.3)